Hello.
Hello.   Where are
you from?
Siberia, Novosibirsk.
Cool, I'm from Khmelnitsky city,
Ukraine.  Is it quiet there in
Novosibirsk?
Yes, it was calm and it still is
calm.
Well, it's far away, yes, so that's cool.  And
how's the deal with gasoline?
Ah, there were problems for 2 weeks, I think.
Now it’s fine, then, um, I
went
to the mountains, to Altai, well, to Altai.   Yes.   There
were problems there too, well, not particularly
serious ones.   I
took a 20 liter canister and didn’t even
need it.
67 rubles  per liter, if you're interested.
Understood.  For example, why do you think
Ukraine attacked Russia?   I
don't discuss politics, if you're interested, then
you should ask the politicians.   What are
you discussing?
Cars, I mostly like Toyota, Opel,
well, I like life in Europe, or what?
The question is, yes, why, why, for example, is
life in Europe better than life in
Russia?
You are very wrong.
And explain.
Lived in Germany from 1919 to
1924, end.   So.   I
want a dacha
with a two-meter fence and a toilet
to spend the night.  All this time, everything
that I listed is
absolutely prohibited.
I bought myself an apartment.
And if everyone else has a white wooden door,
yours will be a white wooden door.  There are bans
absolutely everywhere.  For me it is a
restriction of my freedom, for them it is
laws.
Wait, wait, did I understand correctly that
there are certain requirements for facades so that
they are unified, right?
This is just me as an example
Well, well, it’s just, yes, that is, that is, it
irritates you that, for example, in Russia
you can make one window blue, the other
red, right?   What does this have to do with it
?  Did I mention the window?
Well, about the door as well, about the door as well.
I talked about the public.
About the fence at the dacha.
I said.
Half a meter, no more.   So.
I want I want a two-meter one.
Two meters, got it.  So.
It is forbidden.  I want to spend the night at the dacha, it’s
forbidden.
It is forbidden.   Is
it prohibited to spend the night at the dacha or is it
prohibited to live at the dacha?   You
can't spend the night at the dacha at all.
Just what if, for example, you don’t have time to
leave and spend the night at the dacha?   They'll fine you
.
Understood.  Can't you just live in a dacha, like a
residential one, or can't you even just stay
overnight?
To live There is no talk of life at all.   Yes.
Okay, yes, yes, what time at night
should you leave the dacha?   I do
n’t know, let’s ask Alice,
if No
-no, well, go ahead and ask Alice, I’m
interested.
Alisa,
from what time until what time is it forbidden to spend the night at a
dacha in Germany?   There
is no direct ban on spending the night at a dacha in Germany.  Staying overnight in the
garden house is only allowed on
holidays or weekends.
During the holidays,
Alice, why can't you spend the night at a dacha in
Germany?
According to German law, garden plots are not
intended for residential use.  The houses there are
too small, without running water.
Absolutely right.  That is, it did not live, it is
not residential, it is
absolutely correct.  Just as you can’t
stop in a park, for example.
I bought myself an apartment in Germany.  I
can't change the door.
Certainly.
If everyone has white wooden,
that's right.  You also have white. This is
called a facade.  This is called,
this is called, restricting my freedom.
No, look, you can change the door,
which...
Listen, on your side it will be whatever you
want, but on the entrance side it will be the
same as the standard.
I want a normal one, away from thieves.   A
good door.
Understood.  Listen, what do you think about this
restriction of my freedom?
Got it, got it, got it.  Listen.   That's all
you understood, handsome.
So, the question is, what do you think, for example,
if it’s not allowed
on the street, is that a restriction of freedom?
Those who are visiting, they are right in the
entrance there.
So I'm asking, is the ban on being
on the street a restriction of freedom?
Where?  Again, your freedom
ends where
another person's freedom begins.
Here, here, here, your door, which is a
different color from the doors of the others in
the entrance, yes, this already affects
the public, right?
Public?  My front door?   Yes.
Let it be white and iron.  Okay,
okay.
Wait, who, look, who owns the
house?  Who owns the house?
Who is the owner of the apartment?
So, you are the owner of the apartment.  Who
owns the house and the entrance?
So, to whom?   To
whom?   To
whom?
Co-owners, right?  This is a condominium,
right?  So, it turns out that the entrance, the
facade, the entrance, this is not your
property, right?   The
fact is,
I don’t understand why we’re even discussing this.
Well, because you realized that you were wrong.
There is a fact that for me this is a
limitation of my freedom.
Understood.  Fine.
All.
Moreover, in Germany, for example, you
can’t just buy an air conditioner
and just shove it anywhere.
It is forbidden.  I have a condenser here now, right here
.  I'll show you.   Yes.  For
example, look, why do you,
uh, let's say, you installed an air conditioner
anywhere, where, uh, condensation drips from it
?
Well, it kind of bothers the neighbors.
It interferes, that's it, that's it, that's what you
said, that my freedom ends where the
freedom of another
person begins.  So, when you drip air conditioner
on your neighbor below, you are already
violating his freedom.  Maybe it's because of
these things that in Germany, and in
other countries too, there are some rules,
right?  What can't you do in a con?
Why?
How does spending the night at the dacha get in the way?
No, well, I, for example, am saying.  Listen,
tell me, you bought a car,
can you do whatever you want with it?
Mm, where?
In Russia.
No.
Here.  Is this a restriction of your freedom?
Limitation.
Oh, I get it.  That is, you cannot have his
Freedom does not end where the
freedom of another begins.
Wait, am I right in understanding that you can't
put a flashing light on your
car, you can't
put certain headlights on it, you can't paint it
however you want.  Oh, you don't think these are the same
restrictions as in Germany,
do you?
In Germany, too, these restrictions
exist.
That's right, that's right.
But besides these, there is also a dacha and an
overnight stay.
Got it, got it.  So, do you think that the fact that
you can’t unpack your car
however you want is a restriction of your
freedom in Russia?
What can't I do?   Is the fact
that you can't put a flashing light
on your car a
restriction of your freedom?
Just install a flashing light?   Yes.   No no
.   Is
n't this a restriction of your freedom?   I
just can't
put in a flashing light.
No, look, in Germany you're not allowed to
put up a fence more than half a meter high, and in
Russia you're not allowed to put a
police light on your car.   is
also prohibited.
Yes, yes.  So, do you think that in
Russia
your freedom is being restricted?
Just put a flashing light?  No.
Why?
What you?  In Germany, you can also just
stick in a flashing light.
No, you can't.
But if just the flashing light works
and twitches, well, it
works, yes, yes, of course, yes.
Listen, question, question, why is a
fence, a ban on a fence higher than half a meter, a
restriction of freedom for you, but a ban on your
own flashing light on your car is not
freedom?
Freedom ends where
another person's freedom begins.
So, and?  Why is this a ban for you, but
not this?
Fence.   Well.
What?
Well, what?  Well, a fence.
Well, a fence.
Half a meter.  What is this?   So.
What is this?
What is this?  This is half a meter.   Is
this a restriction of freedom or not?
Well, yes.  If you, look, if you
want to make a big fence 2 m, right?  You're
limiting the view and common space
for people walking down the street,
right?  They shouldn't be walking in a
tunnel, right?  They should walk in such a way that
they have space.  That is,
if you want a
two-meter fence, you limit the
freedom of other people.
How?
You drive them, they have to walk and
look in this tunnel.  The
half-meter limitation is so that people who
walk around feel safe in a
normal space, because
public- Yes, urban public
space.  Ah, and for what purpose?
So that you can see what is growing in
your garden.
What's growing in your garden, they can
see, for example, with a drone, right?
For Germany, so that it can be seen what is
growing in your area.   Yes.
For them it is.
So, you’ll calculate that if it were
75 cm, the Germans wouldn’t see that
you were growing?   A
fence of a certain height so that you can
see, among other things, what
you have growing on it.
That is, if I understand correctly, if
Germany had made a fence half a meter high,
because if it was 75 cm, the Germans would not
have seen what was growing on you.
Anything is possible.
They are at such a level
that it is possible.
Got it, got it.  What other horrors were there in
Germany?
What horrors happened in Germany?  The medicine
was terrible.
Tell.
I'll tell you, easy.
Blood is taken without gloves.   The
medicine was very terrible, but
the equipment was much better than in
Russia.   Yes.
Listen, how is it
that, for example, in
Germany life expectancy is
7-6 years longer than in Russia?   It's
all very simple.  In fact.
Tell.
This is for now, first of all.
Yes, yes, tell me.
These are still some records from those
times.   Yes.
For now, air
plays a very important role.  If the
Altai Mountains were moved here to Novosibirsk,
our
duration would be about the
same.
Understood.  Didn't the Germans
move the Altai Mountains to Dresden, for example?
No, they have mountainous terrain.   Okay
, what are you talking about, don't cry, everything is
fine.
I listen, I listen, well, well,
highlands.
Well, well, well.
Understood.
So, am I correct in understanding that
life expectancy in Altai is the same as in
Germany?
Well, roughly, yes.
No.   Do
you think so?
Let's ask Gemini now.
Well, come on, come on.  Ask Gemini, and I'll ask
Alice.
Let's.
Come on, ask in your own voice, where is the
higher level, longer
life expectancy, in Germany or
in the Altai region?  Go ahead, ask.  Alice
will tell us with her voice now.
I'll ask, but this is not the right data.
Let's ask Alice, come on
.
I'll ask, maybe it will turn out the other way around
, but I'm telling you.
let's ask.  Let's.
Fine.
Let's.
Alisa,
please tell me, what is the
life expectancy of a person in the Altai Mountains?
No, where is it more, in Germany or in the Altai
Mountains?
It is also called Mountain Altai.  Average
life expectancy is 67 years.  Men
live about 62 years, women 73.
Yep.
Women 73.
Right, now let's go to Germany.
I know, Alice, in Germany the
life expectancy of men, let's say a
specific one, no, let's say a specific
continent, because I
asked about Altai.   Let's go to
Dresden.
Well, no, let's take Berlin, for
example.
Come on Berlin, come on Berlin.
Alice, how long do people live in Berlin?
Alice,
life expectancy in Berlin for
men.
In Berlin, men live on average to about
80 years.
Well, and
in Altai
62.63, these are men.
63, that is, look, in Berlin it’s
72.
Correct.  Now ask how many
women there are in Germany, there will be 87, go ahead.
Alice,
life expectancy of women in
Germany, in Berlin.
In Berlin, women live on average about
83 years.
Well, so?
So, look, now we see,
men in Altai live 63 years,
Alisa, all this.
Look, men in Altai live 63 years, in
Berlin 80 years, right?  Men
in Berlin live 17 years longer than in
Altai.   Are
you sure this is up-to-date data?
Wait, well, Alice said that.  Women
immediately said that it was unlikely that this was
Women, women in Altai live 73 years,
in Berlin 83, right?  That is, by 10 years, that
is,
German women live 10 years longer than
Altai women, right?  Berlin men live
17 years longer than Altai men.
17 years old?
Well, yes, 63 and 80, that's what Alice said.   Uh-huh
, uh-huh, well, so-so.   So.
63 and 63 and 80, right?   Yes.
This is 13 years.
So, well, that's it, 13 years.   Well.
80 minus 63 is 13, right?
Well, yes.
So, tell me, how is it that
in Altai there are mountains, air, yes, but there
I explain it 100 times, you don’t seem to hear me
.   I ca
n't hear.
You probably can't hear.  It's very
sad when people don't listen.
Explain.
Let me explain, this is very old data.
Ask Alice, ask Alice what
year this data was for.
Alice,
what year is the data for, when did
80 men live there? Lord,
tell me how to ask the question correctly.
Tell me,
Alice,
what year was the
life expectancy data that you
told me from?
She'll tell you herself now.
Data is approximately for 2020.
2020, okay,
super, come on, 6 years ago.
Look, they haven't changed much in 6 years
.   Has
anything changed there in 6 years?   Come on,
let's get out
of Germany in 6 years.   Come on
, tell her to give more up-to-date
data.
She won't give it.
Understood.
Understood.  Listen,
what kind of microwave do you have, Russian or not
?
This is Russian, it's called Iceberg.
Iceberg?   Yes.   Come on
, really show me.
I can't, I have...
No, bring the microwave.
I have this, I have a computer.
So, can you bring the microwave?
No, am I stupid?  Or a microwave?
No, really a Russian microwave?
The microwave is called Iceberg.   No, it ca
n't be.
I'm telling you, I'm serious.
Please, show me for real, I've never
seen it, I thought you were only Chinese and
Damn, well, I can't, I'm going, what am I
Damn, well,
it's just a minute, please.
Well, what am I supposed to turn off? I'm in my underwear,
first of all, what are you saying?
I'll turn away.
No, but your viewers won’t turn away, what are you saying?
Ah, that’s clever, but what about you, go ahead and move to
the side, hey, put on your underwear and
what are they writing there, by the way?
M?
By the way, I installed air conditioning today.
Come on, let's be happy for
me together, okay?
Air conditioner?   Well.
Got it, cool.  Alice, turn on the
Ukrainian anthem.
What kind of air conditioner is it?
even now.   I
'm playing the national anthem of Ukraine.
Look, one.
Oh, oh, oh, did you see?
Alice, Alice
Alice, volume 10.
Alice, volume, volume zero.
Turn on the Russian anthem.
Alice, turn on the song Putin.
Alice, turn on the Russian anthem.
Alice, turn on Putin.
Scream louder, louder.
I wonder who she listened to?
Alice, fast forward 30 seconds and turn
the volume up to eight.
And the anthem of Ukraine.
Alice, turn on the Ukrainian anthem.
Break off.
No, well, look, the Ukrainian anthem is playing at your home
, you'll get it
.
Break off.
You see, those neighbors will, in short, give you a hard time.
Only the Russian anthem.
You just turned off the sound for me.
You turned off the sound for me, right?
No, no, no.
Alice, stop.
Alice, continue.
Alice, the volume is zero.
Alice, turn on the Ukrainian anthem, volume
10.
Alice, turn it off.
Made.
Turn off, Alice, Alice.
Alisa, turn on the Ukrainian anthem, volume
10.
Alisa, the Russian anthem.
Alisa, turn on the Ukrainian anthem, volume 10
and don't stop.   Go [ __ ] yourself
.   I'm
turning it on.
Like, subscribe, comment.
Subscribe to our WhatsApp channel, here is the
QR code.  There, news
similar to that in the Telegram channel is posted
for those who don’t have Telegram or who don’t
use it for other reasons.
Subscribe to our WhatsApp channel.